# MUHAMMAD RIZQI RAHMATULLAH

089730814733 | muhammad.120130073@student.itera.ac.id | https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-rizqi-rahmatullah-4ba64b24b/ | https://github.com/MRizqi20

Palembang, Sumatera Selatan

I am a curious learner. I am the type of person who always want to know something new and want to make a lot of experience in electricity. I enjoy learn about electrical system control and robotics. I had done a lot of projects about Arduino programming that's made me good in team work and become person that creative, discipline, and persistent. I enjoy on supportive and open-minded environment for my maximal performance. Also, I am looking forward to improve myself to make a grater impact to my environment. "To be a great person, must pass through heavy obstacles".

# **Work Experiences**

# Elictrical Laboratory - ITERA, Lampung Selatan

Aug 2022 - Present

## Laboratory assistant

Electrical Engineering Laboratory helps student to learn about basics and principle of Electrical Engineering. This lab has already equipped measurement and monitoring device. therefore student can learn in that laboratory to improve his electricity skills

- I do mentoring about chemistry experiments spanning more than 80 individuals
- · I succeed teaching all of the participants

#### Chemistry laboratory - ITERA, Lampung Selatan

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

## Chemistry practicum assistant

A room in which there are chemical equipment's are used for experiments. In Laboratory there is a person who take care of it, that person called lab assistant. therefore if there is a chemistry practice the room will be used

- I do mentoring about chemistry experiments spanning more than 50 individuals
- · I succeed teaching all of the participants

# PT. Ozami Inti Sinergi (Indobot Academy) - Yogyakarta

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

#### IoT Engineer

PT Ozami Inti Sinergi is a company engaged in information and communication technology which is a start-up provider of IoT technology education services that has several missions, such as providing the latest Internet of Things e-courses and online Internet of Things workshops based on project based learning. On this occasion PT. Ozami Inti Sinergi (Indobot Academy) opened a certified internship and independent study program (MSIB) Batch 4 organized by the Ministry of Education and Culture with the activity title "Indobot Academy – Internet of Things (IoT) Engineer Camp"

- · IoT Project LED Temperature Monitoring and Control System Using Firebase and MIT App Inventor
- IoT Project in 1 Blynk Interface Controls LED, Buzzer and DHT11 Temperature
- Website Development To Control LED IoT with HTML and CSS code to decorate the website that has been created
- IoT Application Development at MIT App Inventor This project includes making a Loding Screen, Turning on the HP Flashlight through a homemade application
- Indobot Academy Smart Device Final Project Our group made Smart Monitoring IoT Go To Campus with 3 smart light, smart plants, smart fire detector that can monitor campus environment conditions in 1 mobil application interface.

## **Education Level**

#### Institut Teknologi Sumatera - Lampung Selatan, Indonesia

Aug 2020 - Aug 2024

Bachelor Degree in Electrical Engineering, 3.54/4.00

- Current GPA 3.54
- Community service volunteer from the Electrical Engineering department to create and educate the use of solar panels to turn on street lights in Desa Sindang Anom Lampung Timur District
- Member of Division Arduino Training at Unit Robotica in ITERA (2021-2022)
- Head of Human Resource Department at Sriwijaya ITERA (2021-2022)
- Staff of Media and Informatic Department at Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Elektro in ITERA (2021-2022)
- Community service volunteer from the Electrical Engineering department to educate about basic ultrasonic sensor and RC controller for elementary and junior high school
- Participant public workshop about "What Company Looks In You (Interview 101)" organized by XL Axiata Future Leaders (2021)
- Participant national public workshop about "Harmonisasi Dalam Pandemi Untuk Berinovasi" organized by Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Elektro Universitas Sebelas Maret (2021)
- Participant national public workshop about "Power System Competition" organized by "Menyongsong Digitalisasi Sistem Ketenagalistrikan Indonesia Di Era Industri 4.0" organized by Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Elektro Universitas Gadjah Mada (2021)

- Member of Rohis Ukhuwah (2017-2019)
- Head of human resource development Da'i (2018-2019)
- Member of Soccer of Six (2017-2019)
- Member of scientific group (2017-2019)

# Organisational Experience

## Sriwijaya ITERA - ITERA, Lampung Selatan

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

Head of human resource department

• Human resource department is department that create new cadres that have responsibility, solidarity and good in manner for regeneration of UKM Sriwijaya ITERA

## Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Elektro - ITERA, Lampung Selatan

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

Staff of Media and Informatic Department

• Inform about ITERA electrical engineering either inside or outside ITERA. What I am doing is creating an article about Electrical Engineering

#### Unit Robotica ITERA - ITERA, Lampung Selatan

Feb 2021 - Present

Member of Division Arduino Training

· Learn about arduino programming and rafting robot

# Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Achievements @ (2022): Electrical Engineering ITERA Event
- Soft Skills ⊚ (2022): Pemandu Latihan Keterampilan Manajemen Mahasiswa (LKMM ITERA) Kampus Merdeka